<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Hexo Demo</title>
  <subtitle>brutalist blog</subtitle>
  <link href="/notes-from-sfpc/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="http://mhfowler.github.io/notes-from-sfpc/"/>
  <updated>2016-06-21T03:04:11.000Z</updated>
  <id>http://mhfowler.github.io/notes-from-sfpc/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Max Fowler</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>wayback</title>
    <link href="http://mhfowler.github.io/notes-from-sfpc/2016/06/20/wayback/"/>
    <id>http://mhfowler.github.io/notes-from-sfpc/2016/06/20/wayback/</id>
    <published>2016-06-21T01:47:33.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-06-21T03:04:11.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;An image, captured by the wayback machine from 2009, of a website I made in highschool containing&lt;br&gt;now defunct links to songs I recorded in my family house’s&lt;br&gt;closet (also containing the internet router and cleaning supplies), along with some&lt;br&gt;geometric broken image links from the album art I photo-shopped together from&lt;br&gt;heavily filtered images of things around my house:&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20090323231502/http://www.maximusfowler.com/maximusproductions/Music.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;margin-bottom: 5px&quot; src=&quot;/static/remnant.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My freshman and sophomore years of high school I didn’t have many friends &amp;mdash; I spent a lot of time next to the router&lt;br&gt;making angsty electronic music. I kept a small MIDI keyboard and microphone on a fold-able table in the closet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I made hundreds of songs, and used iWeb (apple’s WYISWYG website maker) to make a website to ‘publish’&lt;br&gt;the music to. I spent hours photographing my dog,&lt;br&gt;and random plants and photo-shopping the images together into album art.&lt;br&gt;I put all the songs and album&lt;br&gt;art onto &lt;a href=&quot;http://maximusfowler.com&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;http://maximusfowler.com&lt;/a&gt; and didn’t share the website or music with anyone. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This last spring I looked up maximusfowler.com on the wayback machine and found three entries:&lt;br&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/static/wayback.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I clicked through to Music.html and found the following remnant of a page from 2009:&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://web.archive.org/web/20090323231502/http://www.maximusfowler.com/maximusproductions/Music.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;external&quot;&gt;https://web.archive.org/web/20090323231502/http://www.maximusfowler.com/maximusproductions/Music.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scrolling through the blue letters on the dark background, thinking about echoes&lt;br&gt;of a memory, of looking out the window of my bedroom at night, and an even more distant&lt;br&gt;memory of barefoot stepping on a firecracker and crying, and other memories, of&lt;br&gt;diving into a lake and passing through an unexpected cold patch of water.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perhaps these dark blue letters and empty boxes reverberate my childhood to me&lt;br&gt;more deeply than if all the pages of the site remained.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;An image, captured by the wayback machine from 2009, of a website I made in highschool containing&lt;br&gt;now defunct links to songs I recorde
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>upstart</title>
    <link href="http://mhfowler.github.io/notes-from-sfpc/2016/06/20/upstart/"/>
    <id>http://mhfowler.github.io/notes-from-sfpc/2016/06/20/upstart/</id>
    <published>2016-06-20T18:05:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-06-20T18:06:02.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mhfowler.github.io/westbeth/poems/upstart.html&quot;&gt;http://mhfowler.github.io/westbeth/poems/upstart.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mhfowler.github.io/westbeth/poems/upstart.html&quot;&gt;http://mhfowler.github.io/westbeth/poems/upstart.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>bell labs</title>
    <link href="http://mhfowler.github.io/notes-from-sfpc/2016/06/20/bell%20labs/"/>
    <id>http://mhfowler.github.io/notes-from-sfpc/2016/06/20/bell labs/</id>
    <published>2016-06-20T18:02:09.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-06-20T18:05:11.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;Notes-From-“interactive-art-and-embodiment”-by-Nathaniel-Stern&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Notes-From-“interactive-art-and-embodiment”-by-Nathaniel-Stern&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;Notes From “interactive art and embodiment” by Nathaniel Stern&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;Notes From “interactive art and embodiment” by Nathaniel Stern&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;perception is more than meets the eye &amp;mdash; even with what we traditionally think of as vision&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Body and image mediate one another, and the locus of perception is between, and of, the two&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;‘an ongoing drive to escape flesh’s limitations’ (since descarte and plato)… I argue this escape is pure fantasy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“It was electrical engineer Claude Shannon who first posited a theory of communication whereby information exists in an immaterial form,&lt;br&gt;and which merely needed a vessel to be transmitted”&lt;br&gt;(A Mathematical Theory Of Communication &amp;mdash; Information Theory)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;while data might be replicated or sometimes salvaged, embodiment and the material world cannot be replaced&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“the challenge for new mediat art and theory .. is to move beyond the twin premises of disembodiment and extension in space that continue to qualify both information and corporeality”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;interview-with-claude-shannon&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#interview-with-claude-shannon&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;interview with claude shannon&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;interview with claude shannon&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;Claude Shannon:&lt;br&gt;[telling a story about Alan Turing]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I asked him what he was doing.&lt;br&gt;And he said he was trying to find a way to get better feedback from a computer so he would know what was going on inside the computer.&lt;br&gt;And he’d invented this wonderful command.&lt;br&gt;See, in those days they were working with individual commands.&lt;br&gt;And the idea was to discover good commands.&lt;br&gt;And I said, what is the command? And he said, the command is put a pulse to the hooter, put a pulse to the hooter.&lt;br&gt;Now let me translate that.&lt;br&gt;A hooter is an English, in England is a loudspeaker.&lt;br&gt;And by putting a pulse to it, it would just be put a pulse to a hooter.&lt;br&gt;Now what good is this crazy command?&lt;br&gt;Well, the good of this command is that if you’re in a loop you can have this command in that loop&lt;br&gt;and every time it goes around the loop it will put a pulse in and you will hear a frequency equal to&lt;br&gt;how long it takes to go around that loop. And then you can put another one in some bigger loop and so on.&lt;br&gt;And so you’ll hear all of this coming on and you’ll hear this “boo boo boo boo boo boo,”[CS vocalizing in a sing-song fashion]&lt;br&gt;and his concept was that you would soon learn to listen to that and know whether when it got hung up in a loop or something else or what&lt;br&gt;it was doing all this time, which he’d never been able to tell before.&lt;br&gt;That was a great idea, but I don’t think it was really a very good idea.&lt;br&gt;That command seems to have disappeared from the vocabulary. [laughs]&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&quot;COMPUTING-MACHINERY-AND-INTELLIGENCE&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#COMPUTING-MACHINERY-AND-INTELLIGENCE&quot; class=&quot;headerlink&quot; title=&quot;COMPUTING MACHINERY AND INTELLIGENCE&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;COMPUTING MACHINERY AND INTELLIGENCE&lt;/h3&gt;&lt;p&gt;By A. M. Turing (an excerpt)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The short answer to this argument is that although it is established that there are&lt;br&gt;limitations to the Powers of any particular machine, it has only been stated, without&lt;br&gt;any sort of proof, that no such limitations apply to the human intellect. But I do not&lt;br&gt;think this view can be dismissed quite so lightly. Whenever one of these machines&lt;br&gt;is asked the appropriate critical question, and gives a definite answer, we know that&lt;br&gt;this answer must be wrong, and this gives us a certain feeling of superiority. Is this&lt;br&gt;feeling illusory? It is no doubt quite genuine, but I do not think too much&lt;br&gt;importance should be attached to it. We too often give wrong answers to questions&lt;br&gt;ourselves to be justified in being very pleased at such evidence of fallibility on the&lt;br&gt;part of the machines. Further, our superiority can only be felt on such an occasion&lt;br&gt;in relation to the one machine over which we have scored our petty triumph. There&lt;br&gt;would be no question of triumphing simultaneously over all machines. In short,&lt;br&gt;then, there might be men cleverer than any given machine, but then again there&lt;br&gt;might be other machines cleverer again, and so on&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;h3 id=&quot;Notes-From-“interactive-art-and-embodiment”-by-Nathaniel-Stern&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Notes-From-“interactive-art-and-embodiment”-by-Nathaniel-S
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>start typing</title>
    <link href="http://mhfowler.github.io/notes-from-sfpc/2016/06/20/start%20typing/"/>
    <id>http://mhfowler.github.io/notes-from-sfpc/2016/06/20/start typing/</id>
    <published>2016-06-20T17:53:56.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-06-20T18:05:14.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mhfowler.github.io/westbeth-processing/sketches/vera1/vera1.html&quot;&gt;http://mhfowler.github.io/westbeth-processing/sketches/vera1/vera1.html&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://mhfowler.github.io/westbeth-processing/sketches/vera1/vera1.html&quot;&gt;http://mhfowler.github.io/westbeth-processing/sketches/
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>yarn</title>
    <link href="http://mhfowler.github.io/notes-from-sfpc/2016/06/20/yarn/"/>
    <id>http://mhfowler.github.io/notes-from-sfpc/2016/06/20/yarn/</id>
    <published>2016-06-20T17:30:53.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-06-20T17:44:21.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;inspired by daniel temkin’s interest in esolangs, we had a homework assignment to design a new programming language.&lt;br&gt;this is a programming language made out of yarn and pipe-cleaners&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/R10Ctv9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; title=&quot;Logo Title Text 1&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;inspired by daniel temkin’s interest in esolangs, we had a homework assignment to design a new programming language.&lt;br&gt;this is a program
    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>goodmorning</title>
    <link href="http://mhfowler.github.io/notes-from-sfpc/2016/06/10/goodmorning/"/>
    <id>http://mhfowler.github.io/notes-from-sfpc/2016/06/10/goodmorning/</id>
    <published>2016-06-10T04:31:55.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-06-20T18:51:21.000Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;computers are illusion machines&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;computers are illusion machines&lt;/p&gt;

    
    </summary>
    
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
